# SARTHAK MUDGAL

Teacher, Percussionist, Composer, Arranger

Address – Emaar Palm Garden , Sec -83 , Gurugram, 122004

Email:

smudgal1991@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

My experience boasts of the various musical performances that I have accomplished- be it alone, with bands, with greats or in ensembles. I have been associated with music right from when I was 3 years of age. I started with Tabla and later branched into other instruments of percussion. I was selected as the Presidential Scholar by AR Rahman for a Diploma at Berklee College of Music. I have experiences in composing and arranging Music of various Genres

## **SKILLS**

- Play 20 different kinds of Indian Classical & Indo African Instruments.
- Music Composer / Arranger.
- Music / Event Management.
- Music Therapy

#### MUSICAL EXPERIENCE

- ✓ CMPA Assistant with Berklee City Music Program at Boston Arts Academy 2017
- ✓ Berklee Beantown Jazz Festival September 30th, 2017
- ✓ Music Composer at AIR The National Radio Channel of India, 2014-2015
- ✓ Lead Drummer for internationally acclaimed band Maati Baani, Mumbai, India.
- ✓ Lead Drummer for Music Director Shankar Mahadevan.
- ✓ Lead Percussionist For Composer Rekha Bhardwaj.
- ✓ Assistant Music Composer for Sony Series Maharana Pratap.
- ✓ Lead Percussionist for Maestro Sri Ram lyyer.



I composed and arranged this piece about agony and suffering, in keeping with the melody of life.

YouTube Views: 31K



Had the opportunity to not only be in the same ensemble with the great Tigran Hamasyan but also arranged and played guitar/percussion for the performance. **YouTube Views: 313K** 



Composed and arranged an amalgamation of traditiona and contemporary music performance from Turkey, Egypt, Bulgaria, Tunisia and India. **YouTube Views: 48K** 

### **Professional Experience:**

- ✓ Front Desk/Office Assistant at The Be ;rklee Alumni Affairs Office (2017-2018)
  - Played a vital role in managing and organizing alumni database and helped students successfully maintain their student status.
- ✓ CMPA Assistant with Berklee City Music Program at Boston Arts Academy (2017-2018)
  - Successfully instructed and managed a group of approximately 20 students and supervised a teaching team.
  - Collaborated with students and instructors to prepare a performance each semester.
  - Contributed to the development of the syllabus and the curriculum to help students reach their goals.
- Music Composer at AIR, the National Radio Channel of India (2014)
  - Directed and composed music for a non-profit organization, "Going To School" in collaboration with the National Radio Channel of India.

### **HOBBIES**

Everything music

### **Accomplishments:**

- A.R. Rahman Presidential Scholarship at Berklee College of Music, Boston, MA,2016
- Award for "Best Newcomer Musician" Aircel NH7 Music Festival, 2015
- Award for "Best Percussionist of India" IRAA Awards, 2014
- Awarded for "Most Creative Artist of India" Songdew, 2014
- Special Mentioned in the Guitar World Magazine, Van halen Edition
   2020 By Lead guitar Player Adam Jones from the Band TOOL.
- Special Mention by Sitar Maestro Niladri Kumar on collaboration on his new single Raghupati Raghav Raja Ram.
- Special Mention by Renowned Drummer Eric Moore on covering his Famous Track Get Your Freak On.
- Featured and Composed music in Commercial Advertisements for Havells India and Noise Headphones.
- Played as a Guest Artist for John Mayer at Berklee Performance Clinic.

#### **Voluntary Work:**

- Music Co-writer for International Documentaries, 2012
- Fundraising for New Delhi Infants Orphanage, 2010 2012
- Percussion Workshops for school students across India 2019 Present

#### **Education:**

- Berklee College of Music 2016-2019
- University of Delhi, India, 2010-2013
- University of Allahabad, India 2006-2009